In this video, we will see how to insure
any type of vehicle through CSC. So,
in this video, we are going to show the latest process of insuring any type of vehicle. So,
let's start. First, you have to
open the CSC digital service portal. Then
you have to click on the insurance type
and here you have to click on the third party insurance
option.
Many insurance companies will be
shown here in front of you. So, here we are going to
complete our insurance through the IIC board. So,
in our case, we will
insure the car. So, click on the third party
insurance option.
Here, if we
insure any vehicle through ICICI, then first of all
we enter the vehicle number of that vehicle, that is, the
number which is written on the plate, we have to type it completely here. Then
you have to click on the option of the French details. If
any
type of detail seems incorrect here, then
you can correct it. Then you have to
click on the option of Get Quote.
As soon as you click, the premium amount of that vehicle will be shown here.
Here we are insuring the car for ₹ 4471,
so we have to pay it, then
you have to click on the proceed option. First of all,
we have to
complete the KYC of the owner of this vehicle,
so here first of all we can do his KYC through his Aadhar number
or PAN number or any other document,
so
we are going to do his KYC through PAN card here,
so first of all
we have to enter the PAN card number here
and in the second option,
whatever his date of birth is registered on his PAN card, we will enter that date of
birth, then you have to
click on the submit option, if he does
not have a PAN card, then he
can also do his KYC through his Aadhar card,
click on the option of complete details of the vehicle
owner as per the documents,
so if you find everything correct here, then
you have to click on the proceed option, then
KYC here  It has been confirmed complete
here,
some of their additional details will also have to be entered here, so first of all
you will have to
enter their mobile number here and
entering email ID here is optional, you will
definitely have to enter email ID here, so
after entering mobile number and email ID,
you have to click on the generate proposal option here,
as soon as you click, the
next page will be opened here, so to make ₹
24 ₹ 1 payment here,
we have to click on the proceed option, so
here we have to enter the password of our CSC here,
after that
we have to enter the MPIN of the password here, then
₹ 71 will be deducted from our CSC wallet
here, as soon as we enter the password and MPIN,
₹ 71 has been deducted from our CSC wallet
and our
insurance, which is the insurance of our vehicle here, has been
successfully completed,
or if we have to download the insurance receipt here, then
We have to
click on the download option, so here the
complete receipt of insurance has been downloaded,
which we
can print and keep with us. Here in front of us,
we have
completed our insurance of our vehicle through IIC Lumbard,
so the
complete insurance certificate of ICICI has been
opened here, so here the complete details of the
person through whom this insurance has been done, i.e. at
whichever CSC center this
insurance has been done, will be
shown here and here the complete
details of the vehicle, i.e. the person whose insurance has been done here, will also be shown here. This
insurance is valid for one year, i.e. for one year,
we have to get it renewed later also
because you
can see here that we have shown you the complete insurance of a car here
in the live process,
which you can
complete your insurance here through this medium.
Here, we have to print and give the complete certificate of whichever person we
will insure here,
if you have it on this  If you have the CSC seal then you have to
put it, otherwise you have to print it in black and
colour on any page here and
give it to me, so
thank you very much for watching the video, Jai Hind